pretty drunk
you feel okay i'm giggly and there's
gaps
in my memory i'm sorry already okay so
uh let's get back so yorktown
we won well now we've got to form a
country
um they all ask him hey come be part of
the constitutional convention
so we're figuring out how the american
system is going to work
the constitutional convention this is
the room where they're deciding what the
shape of our government should be
they're hashing it out and hamilton
speaks for six
hours but some of the things he pitched
would haunt him the rest of his career
he pitched
maybe president for life
a monarchist maybe
uh we inherit positions
that's terrible this guy just
wants to bring back the british
those whispers are from the perspectives
of uh people who don't like him
um but anyway we adopt the system that
we adopt and hamilton
becomes its most ardent defender
so trying to find the
straightest line through this story
so hamilton has an affair
um while he's a treasury secretary he
carries on this affair with a woman
named mariah reynolds
her husband shows up he's like yo
[Music]
uh that's my wife i'm happy to like keep
it on the low
but you have to pay me it's basically
extorted for about a thousand dollars
james reynolds the husband who is
extorting him
gets arrested on some other
while he's trying to
weasel his way out of it he says i've
got dirt on alexander hamilton
everyone goes really hamilton
uh as has been embezzling and he sort of
says all this about hamilton um and
so three guys
go to confront hamilton on these charges
one of the dudes was
future president james monroe no yo
hamilton we know what you did you know
what you did
check out these checks to james reynolds
what's up
and they accuse him of embezzling funds
and hamilton goes no no i was just
this lady and her husband was
hitting me up for money
i didn't touch american money and i have
all kinds of proof
and he like vomits information all over
them
oh wow that was more than we needed to
hear
and we're good thanks the info about the
affair
gets somehow miraculously printed in the
paper
hamilton is not a great dude
i know you think he's great because he's
a war vet and he's the treasury
secretary but
you're gonna learn the truth real soon
and hamilton gets this and he goes to
james monroe
like i told you that in secret and james
monroe was like it wasn't secret
it wasn't me wasn't me who who uh
published it
i told three people about
this
and you're the one who was taking notes
so i know it came from you
like fess up
so hamilton over sharer writes the
reynolds pamphlet
the whole thing reads like a dear
penthouse letter like dear
america i never thought this would
happen to me
but one day this ripped bonus woman
showed up at my door saying oh my
husband's beating me left me alone and i
need money and i need to help
you are a man of honor can you help me
hamilton's like
i could give her money or i could and
either one would be acceptable
the reynolds pamphlet is like dick 101
and by the way
he said this to his friends being like
hey i think i'm going to publish this
and everyone was like hey bro i don't
think this is a good idea to publish
this
like maybe your wife and your seven
children would not love it if you
publish this
and hamilton's like wow like i got
accused of embezzling
like i can't let that stand maybe the
like marital infidelity trumps that
i know it doesn't in your head but to
everyone else in the world it does
um and he's like no i can't let that
stand
and hamilton goes back to james monroe
and now
hamilton's like well it's all out in the
open um and if you still want to settle
this because i know you're the one who
leaked it
um monroe's like well i didn't leak it
but if you want to like fight like let's
do this
and so they meet face to face and monroe
goes all right you're mad at me
because of this this and this and
hamilton goes let's start at the
beginning
and lists like the first time they met
he lists the details of the entire
meeting as monroe gets more and more
impatient monroe's like i know all this
they know all this
i know all this hamilton's like
you interrupted me i have to start again
monroe is getting angry and angry until
they're finally pulled apart
because they're about to like punch each
other in the face so monroe
goes to his homie aaron burr and goes yo
you know hamilton you tell him this is
so like
high school gossip he goes will you tell
hamilton
that if he's challenging me to a duel i
accept
but if he's not i wasn't challenging him
to a duel and goes over to hamilton like
james monroe told me to tell you
that if you're challenging him he
accepts but if you weren't challenging
him
he doesn't really want to go into a duel
uh and burr squashes the duel
burr's like duels are stupid and you
both should just
like shut up and it's over and hamilton
told everyone everything
anyway so there's no point in you
shooting at each other
sorry i gotta put my phone on vibrate
okay
oh quest loves questlove text me
you did drunk history what how did
kessler find out oh here we go
quest love
history has its eyes on you
yes this is awesome bye questo